window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "Data_Structure - Stack",
  "duration": 91,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Stack",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>Consider a stack data structure into which we can PUSH and POP records. Assume that each record pushed in the stack has a positive integer key and that all keys are distinct.  <br>\nWe wish to augment the stack data structure with an \\(O(1) \\) time MIN operation that returns a pointer to the record with the smallest key present in the stack  <br><br>\n1) without deleting the corresponding record, and  <br>\n2) without increasing the complexities of the standard stack operations.  <br><br>\nWhich one or more of the following approach(es) can achieve it? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2025 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Keep with every record in the stack, a pointer to the record with the smallest key below it.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Keep a pointer to the record with the smallest key in the stack.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Keep an auxiliary array in which the key values of the records in the stack are maintained in sorted order.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Keep a Min-Heap in which the key values of the records in the stack are maintained.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Keep with every record in the stack, a pointer to the record with the smallest key below it.</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/460800/gate-cse-2025-set-2-question-35#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Let S1 and S2 be two stacks. S1 has capacity of 4 elements. S2 has capacity of\n2 elements. S1 already has 4 elements: 100, 200, 300, and 400, whereas S2 is\nempty, as shown below.<br><br>\n\\(\n\\begin{array}{|c|}\n\\hline  400 (Top)  \\\\\n\\hline  300 \\\\\n\\hline  200\\\\\n\\hline  100 \\\\\n\\hline\n\\end{array}\\)<br>Stack S1\n<br>\n<br>\n\\(\n\\begin{array}{|c|}\n\\hline    \\\\\n\\hline    \\\\\n\\hline\n\\end{array}\\)<br>Stack S2\n<br><br>\nOnly the following three operations are available:<br>\n<br>PushToS2: Pop the top element from S1 and push it on S2.\n<br>PushToS1: Pop the top element from S2 and push it on S1.\n<br>GenerateOutput: Pop the top element from S1 and output it to the\nuser.<br><br>\nNote that the pop operation is not allowed on an empty stack and the push operation\nis not allowed on a full stack.\n<br><br>Which of the following output sequences can be generated by using the above\noperations? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2024 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>100, 200, 400, 300</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>200, 300, 400, 100</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>400, 200, 100, 300</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>300, 200, 400, 100</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>200, 300, 400, 100</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/422859/gate-cse-2024-set-2-question-38#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Consider the operator precedence and associativity rules for the integer arithmetic operators given in the table below.<br>\n\\(\\begin{array}{|c|l|l|}\n\\hline Operator &amp; Precedence &amp; Associativity \\\\\n\\hline+ &amp; Highest &amp; Left \\\\\n\\hline- &amp; High &amp; Right \\\\\n\\hline* &amp; Medium &amp; Right \\\\\n\\hline  /  &amp; Low &amp; Right \\\\\n\\hline\n\\end{array}\n\\)<br>\nThe value of the expression \\(3+1+5 * 2 / 7+2-4-7-6 / 2 \\) as per the above rules is _____ <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2024 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "6",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/422819/gate-cse-2024-set-1-question-23#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following sequence of operations on an empty stack.<br><br>push(54); push(52); pop(); push(55); push(62); s=pop();<br><br>\nConsider the following sequence of operations on an empty queue.\n<br><br>\nenqueue(21); enqueue(24); dequeue(); enqueue(28); enqueue(32); q=dequeue();<br><br>\nThe value of s+q is ___________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2021 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "86",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/357430/gate-cse-2021-set-1-question-21#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>A stack is implemented with an array of \\({ }^{\\prime} A[0 \\ldots N-1]^{\\prime}\\) and a variable \\(\\text { 'pos'. }\\) The push and pop operations are defined by the following code.<br><pre><code> push (x)\n    A[pos] &lt;- x\n    pos &lt;- pos -1\nend push\npop()\n    pos &lt;- pos+1\n    return A[pos]\nend pop</code></pre><br>Which of the following will initialize an empty stack with capacity N for the above implementation? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2020)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\text { pos } \\leftarrow-1\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(\\text { pos } \\leftarrow 0\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\text { pos } \\leftarrow 1\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\text { pos } \\leftarrow N-1\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\text { pos } \\leftarrow N-1\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/331311/isro2020-72\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Convert the pre-fix expression to in-fix \\(-^{*}+A B C^{*}-D E+F G\\) <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2020)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\((A-B)^{*} C+\\left(D^{*} E\\right)-(F+G)\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\((A+B)^{*} C-(D-E)^{*}(F-G)\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\((A+B-C)^{*}(D-E)^{*}(F+G)\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\((((A+B)*C)-((D-E)*(F+G)))\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>\\((((A+B)*C)-((D-E)*(F+G)))\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "Originally all Options are wrong. We have modified one option.<br><a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/331339/isro2020-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Choose the equivalent prefix form of the following expression<br>\\((a+(b-c))^{\\star}((d-e) /(f+g-h))\\) <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\({ }^{\\star}+a-b c /-d e-+f g h\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\({ }^{\\star}+a-b c -/d e-+f g h\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\({ }^{\\star}+a-b c /-ed-+f g h\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\({ }^{*}+\\mathrm{ab}-\\mathrm{c} /-\\mathrm{de}-+\\mathrm{fgh}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>\\({ }^{\\star}+a-b c /-d e-+f g h\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128769/isro2017-69\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>The best data structure to check whether an arithmetic expression has  balanced parenthesis is  a: <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Queue</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Stack</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Tree</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>List</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>Stack</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128743/isro2017-59\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>The following postfix expression with single digit operands is evaluated using a stack:<br>\\(8 \\ 2 \\ 3 \\ \\;\\hat{}\\; / \\ 2 \\ 3 * + 5 \\ 1 * -\\)<br>Note that \\(\\hat{}\\;\\) is the exponentiation operator. The top two elements of the stack after the first * is evaluated are <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2016)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>6,1</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>5,7</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>3,2</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>1,5</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>6,1</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1236/gate2007-38-isro2016-27\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>If the sequence of operations - push (1), push (2), pop, push (1), push (2), pop, pop, pop, push (2), pop are performed on a stack, the sequence of popped out values <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2015)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>2,2,1,1,2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>2,2,1,2,2</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>2,1,2,2,1</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>2,1,2,2,2</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>2,2,1,1,2</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/51080/isro2015-11\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>The result evaluating the postfix expression 10    5  +  60     6   /  *  8 -   is <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-3)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>284</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>213</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>142</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>71</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>142</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8408/gate2015-3-18#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>The five items: A, B, C, D, and E are pushed in a stack, one after other starting from A. The stack is popped four items and each element is inserted in a queue. The two elements are deleted from the queue and pushed back on the stack. Now one item is popped from the stack. The popped item is <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2014)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>A</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>B</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>C</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>D</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>D</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/49487/isro2007-16-isro2009-30-isro2014-43\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>Suppose a stack implementation supports an instruction REVERSE, which reverses the order\nof elements on the stack, in addition to the PUSH and POP instructions. Which one of the\nfollowing statements is TRUE with respect to this modified stack? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>A queue cannot be implemented using this stack.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>A queue can be implemented where ENQUEUE takes a single instruction and\nDEQUEUE takes a sequence of two instructions.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>A queue can be implemented where ENQUEUE takes a sequence of three instructions\nand DEQUEUE takes a single instruction</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>A queue can be implemented where both ENQUEUE and DEQUEUE take a single\ninstruction each.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>A queue can be implemented where ENQUEUE takes a sequence of three instructions\nand DEQUEUE takes a single instruction</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2007/gate2014-2-41#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>The five items: A, B, C, D, and E are pushed in a stack, one after other starting from A. The stack is popped four items and each element is inserted in a queue. The two elements are deleted from the queue and pushed back on the stack. Now one item is popped from the stack. The popped item is <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2009)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>A</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>B</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>C</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>D</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>D</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/49487/isro2007-16-isro2009-30-isro2014-43\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>The expression \\(1 * 2 \\wedge 3 * 4 \\wedge 5 * 6\\) will be evaluated as <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2009)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(32^{30}\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(162^{30}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>49152</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>173458</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>49152</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/48052/isro2009-32\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 16,
          "question": "<p>The five items: A, B, C, D, and E are pushed in a stack, one after other starting from A. The stack is popped four items and each element is inserted in a queue. The two elements are deleted from the queue and pushed back on the stack. Now one item is popped from the stack. The popped item is <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2009)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>A</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>B</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>C</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>D</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>D</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/49487/isro2007-16-isro2009-30-isro2014-43\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 17,
          "question": "<p>The infix expression \\(A+(B-C)^*D\\) is correctly represented in prefix notation as <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2009)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(A+B-C*D\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(+A*-BCD\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(ABC-D*+\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(A+BC-D*\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(+A*-BCD\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/50380/isro2009-28\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 18,
          "question": "<p>Assume that the operators \\(+, -, \\times\\) are left associative and \\(\\hat{}\\) is right associative. The order of precedence (from highest to lowest) is \\(\\hat{}, \\times, +, -\\). The postfix expression corresponding to the infix expression \\(a+ b \\times c-d \\;\\;  \\hat{} e \\; \\; \\hat{} \\; \\; f\\) is <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2009)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(abc\\times+def\\;\\hat{}\\;\\;\\hat{}-\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(abc\\times + de \\;\\; \\hat{} f \\;\\; \\hat{}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\( ab+c\\times d-e\\;\\; \\hat{} f \\;\\; \\hat{}\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(-+a\\times bc\\;\\;\\hat{}\\;\\;\\hat{}def\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(abc\\times+def\\;\\hat{}\\;\\;\\hat{}-\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1035/gate2004-38-isro2009-27\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 19,
          "question": "<p>Stack A has the entries a, b, c (with a on top). Stack B is empty. An entry popped out of stack A can be printed immediately or pushed to stack B. An entry popped out of the stack B can be only be printed. In this arrangement, which of the following permutations of a, b, c are not possible? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>b a c</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>b c a</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>c a b</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>a b c</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>c a b</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/50138/isro2008-70\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 20,
          "question": "<p>The five items: A, B, C, D, and E are pushed in a stack, one after other starting from A. The stack is popped four items and each element is inserted in a queue. The two elements are deleted from the queue and pushed back on the stack. Now one item is popped from the stack. The popped item is <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>A</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>B</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>C</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>D</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>D</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/49487/isro2007-16-isro2009-30-isro2014-43\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 21,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following C program: <br><pre><code> #include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\n\n           #define EOF -1\n           void push (int); /* push the argument on the stack */\n           int pop  (void); /* pop the top of the stack */\n           void flagError ();\n           int main ()\n          {         int c, m, n, r;\n                     while ((c = getchar ()) != EOF)\n                    { if  (isdigit (c) )\n                               push (c);\n                     else if ((c == '+') || (c == '*'))\n                    {          m = pop ();\n                                n = pop ();\n                                r = (c == '+') ? n + m : n*m;\n                                push (r);\n                      }\n                      else if (c != ' ')\n                               flagError ();\n             }\n              printf(\"% c\", pop ());\n}</code></pre> <br>What is the output of the program for the following input?<br>5 2 * 3 3 2 + * + <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>15</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>25</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>30</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>150</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>25</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3465/gate2007-it-32\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 22,
          "question": "<p>The following postfix expression with single digit operands is evaluated using a\nstack:<pre><code>\n8 2 3 ^ / 2 3 * + 5 1 * -  </code></pre>\nNote that ^ is the exponentiation operator. The top two elements of the stack\nafter the first * is evaluated are: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>6,1</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>5, 7</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>3, 2</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>1, 5</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>6,1</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1236/gate2007-38#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 23,
          "question": "<p>A function \\(f\\) defined on stacks of integers satisfies the following properties. \\(f(\\emptyset) = 0\\) and \\(f (push (S, i)) = max (f(S), 0) + i\\) for all stacks \\(S\\) and integers \\(i\\).If a stack \\(S\\) contains the integers 2, -3, 2, -1, 2 in order from bottom to top, what is \\(f(S)\\)? <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2005)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>6</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>4</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>3</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>2</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>3</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3758/gate2005-it-13\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 24,
          "question": "<p>A program attempts to generate as many permutations as possible of the string, 'abcd' by pushing the characters a,b,c,d in the same order onto a stack, but it may pop off the top character at any time. Which one of the following strings CANNOT be generated using this program? <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2004)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>abcd</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>dcba</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>cbad</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>cabd</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>cabd</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3695/gate2004-it-52\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 25,
          "question": "<p>Assume that the operators +, -, x , are left associative and ^ is right associative. the order of\nprecedence (from highest to lowest) is ^, x , +, -. The postfix expression corresponding to the infix\nexpression a + b x c-d^e^f is <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2004)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>abcx+def^^-</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>abcx+de^f^-</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>ab+cxd-e^f^</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>axbc^^def</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>abcx+def^^-</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1035/gate2004-38#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 26,
          "question": "<p>The best data structure to check whether an arithmetic expression has balanced parentheses is a <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2004)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>queue</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>stack</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>tree</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>list</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>stack</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1002/gate2004-5#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 27,
          "question": "<p>A single array A[1...MAXSIZE] is used to implement two stacks. The two stacks grow from opposite\nends of the array. Variables top1 and top 2 (top1 \\(\\lt\\) top 2) point to the location of the topmost\nelement in each of the stacks. If the space is to be used efficiently, the condition for \"stack full\" is <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2004)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>(top1 = MAXSIZE/2) and (top2 = MAXSIZE/2+1)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>(top1 + top2 = MAXSIZE</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>(top1 = MAXSIZE/2) or (top2 = MAXSIZE)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>top1 = top2 -1</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>top1 = top2 -1</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1000/gate2004-3#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 28,
          "question": "<p>Let S be a stack of size n \\(\\geq\\) 1. Starting with the empty stack, suppose we push the first n natural numbers in sequence, and then perform n pop operations. Assume\nthat Push and Pop operation take X seconds each , and Y seconds elapse between\nthe end of the one such stack operation and the start of the next operation. For\nm \\(\\geq\\) 1, define the stack-life of m as the time elapsed from the end or Push (m) to the start of the pop operation that removes m from S . The average stack-life of\nan element of this stack is <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2003)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>n(X+Y)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>3Y+2X</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>n(X+Y)-X</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Y+2X</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>n(X+Y)-X</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/951/gate2003-64#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 29,
          "question": "<p>To evaluate an expression without any embedded function calls <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2002)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>One stack is enough</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Two stack are needed</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>As many stacks as the height of the expression tree are needed</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>A Turning machine is needed in the general case</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>One stack is enough</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/849/gate2002-2-19#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 30,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following is essential for converting an infix expression to the postfix form efficiently? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1997)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>An operator stack</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>An operand stack</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>An operand stack and an operator stack</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>A parse tree</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>An operator stack</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2223/gate1997-1-7\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 31,
          "question": "<p>The postfix expression for the infix expression A+B*(C+D)/F+D*E is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>AB + CD + *F/D +E*</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>ABCD + *F/DE* ++</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>A * B + CD/F *DE ++</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>A + *BCD/F* DE ++</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>ABCD + *F/DE* ++</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2633/gate1995-2-21\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 32,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following permutations can be obtained in the output (in the same order) using a stack assuming that the input is the sequence 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 in that order? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1994)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>3, 4, 5, 1, 2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>3, 4, 5, 2, 1</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>1, 5, 2, 3, 4</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>5, 4, 3, 1, 2</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>3, 4, 5, 2, 1</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2457/gate1994-1-14\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 33,
          "question": "<p>Choose the correct alternatives (more than one may be correct) and write the corresponding letters only:\n<br>The following sequence of operations is performed on a stack:<br>\nPUSH  (10), PUSH (20), POP, PUSH (10), PUSH (20), POP, POP, POP, PUSH (20), POP<br>\nThe sequence of values popped out is<br> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1991)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>20,10,20,10,20</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>20,20,10,10,20</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>10,20,20,10,20</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>20,20,10,20,10</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>20,20,10,10,20</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/522/gate1991-03-vii\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
